<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!--  Main Course Recipes  -->
    <string name="Main1">Butter Chicken</string>
    <string name="Mainingredients1">
\n3-4 Chicken Breasts/ Thighs boneless
\n1 Tbsp Ginger-Garlic paste
\n2 tsp Chili Powder Kashmiri Chilli or a mix of Cayenne &amp; Paprika
\n2 Tbsp Greek Yogurt plain
\n1 Lime juiced
\nSalt to taste
\n1/2 inch Cinnamon Stick
\n2-3 Cloves
\n2-3 Green Cardamom Pods
\n1 Bay Leaf
\n1/4 cup Butter
\n1 medium Onion diced
\n1 Tbsp Ginger-Garlic paste
\n1-2 green chillies (thai)
\n1 (15oz) can Tomato Puree (not suace)
\n6-8 cashews soaked in hot water
\n1 Tbsp Coriander Powder
\n1/2 tsp Cumin powder
\n2 tsp Red chili powder (mix of cayenne &amp; Paprika works)
\n2 Tbsp Sugar
\nChicken stock/water
\n1/2 cup heavy cream
\n1 handful fresh cilantro chopped


    </string>
    <string name="Mainserving1">4 serving(s) </string>
    <string name="Maintime1">Prep Time: 30 minutes , Total Time: 45 minutes </string>
    <string name="Maindirections1">
\nFor the Chicken:
\nStep 1 :Mix the garlic-ginger, chili powder, yogurt, salt and lime juice to make a paste. Apply it to the chicken pieces (keeping them whole or in big pieces for easy grilling) , marinate and let itsit for at least 30 mins or longer.
\n\n Step 2: Once  marinated cook on high heat on the grill to get a charred flavor. The chicken does not need to cook all the way through, you will be cubing and finishing it in the sauce.
\n For the Sauce:
\n\n Step 3 : \nHeat half the butter and a couple spoons of oil in a pot.
\n\n Step 4 : \nOnce hot add all the whole spices and let them sizzle, then immediately add the diced onion and sauté until translucent  and soft.
\n\n Step 5 : \nAdd the ginger-garlic paste and fry for 1-2 minutes.
\n\n Step 6 : \nAdd the chilli peppers, 1 can tomato puree and all the ground spices and sugar. stir and cover and cook for about 20 minutes stirring occasionally. basically let all the flavors meld together and cook down until you start seeing a little oil or butter separating from the mixture.
\n\n Step 7 : \nAdd the soaked cashews with the water and about a cup or so of chicken stock or water. Boil with a cover for another 15 mins.
\n\n Step 8 : \nTurn off heat and let the mixture cool enough to be able to blend it into a smooth sauce or if you have an immersion blender just blend in the pot directly.
\n\n Step 9 : \nOnce blended smooth return the sauce to the pot and bring to a boil, adjust consistency with water/stock.
\n\n Step 10 : \nDice the grilled chicken pieces and add it to the curry with all the chicken juices and blackened bits.
\n\n Step 11 : \nStir in the remaining butter and crush dried fenugreek leaves over the top. Cover &amp; simmer for 10-15 mins.
\n\n Step 12 : \nTurn heat to low and add heavy cream to finish the dish. heat through, but don/t boil.
\n\n Step 13 : \nTurn off heat and garnish with chopped cilantro.\n
    </string>
    <string name="Main2">Cuban Mojo Roast Chicken</string>
    <string name="Mainingredients2">
        \n 1 small (4-5 lb) young Chicken
        \n7-8 cloves of Peeled Garlic
        \n1 cup fresh Cilantro
        \n1/4 cup fresh Mint leaves
        \n 1 Orange, zest &amp; juice
        \n1 Lime, zest &amp; juice
        \n1/2 Jalapcno, dc-seeded
        \n1 Tbsp dried Oregano
        \n2 tsp Cumin powder
        \n1 tsp smoked/sweet Paprika
        \nSalt &amp; Pepper, to taste
        \n1 Red Onion 2 Bell Peppers
        \n2 Bell Peppers


    </string>
    <string name="Mainserving2">4 serving(s) </string>
    <string name="Maintime2">Prep Time: 15 minutes , Total Time: 2 hours </string>
    <string name="Maindirections2" >
    Step1:
    \nTo butterfly the chicken: Simply cut out the back bone starting from the cavity up to the neck with a good pair of kitchen shears. Then turn the bird cut-side down and using the heel of your hand or both hands, flatten the breast bone.
    \n \n Step 2:
    \nFor the Marinade: Add the garlic, cilantro, mint, orange zest &amp; juice, lime zest &amp; juice, jalapeno, dried oregano, cumin powder, smoked/sweet paprika, salt and pepper to a food processor and pulse till everything is finely chopped.
    \n \n Step 3:\n
    Marinate the chicken well on both sides and set it aside in the refrigerator to marinate for at least 1 hour or up to overnight.
    \n \n Step 4:\n
    Pre-heat your oven to 400°F
    \n \n Step 5:\n
    Slice the onion &amp; bell peppers into thick strips and layer the bottom of an ovenproof skillet/dish with them.
    \n \n Step 6:\n
    Place the chicken on top of the veggies and pour all the marinade into the pan as well.
    \n \n Step 7:\n
    Roast at 400°F for 45-60 minutes until the internal temperature registers 165°F
    \n \n Step 8:\n
    Let the chicken rest covered for 10 minutes, then serve hot.
    \n \n Bonus tip:\n
    The chicken pairs really well over rice or as a healthier option with roasted sweet potato, black beans (leave out for Whole30/Paleo) and pineapple salsa.\n
    </string>
    <string name="Main3">Rogan Josh</string>
    <string name="Mainingredients3">
        \n2 lbs mutton/meat (washed and cubed)
\n2tbsp Ghee + 2 tbsp oil
\n4-5 Shallots (finely sliced)
\n2 tsp ginger garlic paste
\n2 tbsp Kashmiri red chilli powder
\n1- 1.5 tsp fennel powder
\n 1/2 tsp dry ginger powder
\n1/2 cup yogurt (whisked well)
\n1.25 cups water
\npinch of saffron (optional)
\nsalt - to taste
\n A handful of chopped coriander leaves, for garnish
        \n\n For Garam Masala:
\n1" Cinnamon stick
 3 cloves
 3-4 green cardamom
 1 Tsp Cumin Seeds
1-2 Black Cardamoms
1 bay leaf
    </string>
    <string name="Mainserving3">4 serving(s) </string>
    <string name="Maintime3">Prep Time: 15 minutes , Total Time: 1 hour </string>
    <string name="Maindirections3" >
        Step 1: \n
\nPowder the whole spices/ garam masala (Cinnamon, cloves, green cardamom &amp; Cumin Seeds) together excluding the black cardamom and bay leaf &amp; set aside.
\n\n Step 2: \n
        In another small bowl, add the Kashmiri Chilli powder, fennel seed powder and ginger powder with 1/4 cup of water and mix together.
\n\n Step 2: \nIn a heavy bottom pot, heat the ghee &amp; oil on medium high then add the black cardamom &amp; bay leaf to the oil.
\n\n Step 3: \nThen add the sliced shallots and fry them on medium-low heat until they start caramelizing and turning golden brown. (This takes a good 8-10 minutes so be patient, but do not turn up the heat)
\n\n Step 4: \nAdd the ginger garlic paste and fry for a minute or two.
\n\n Step 5: \nThen add in the mutton (goat meat)/ lamb cubes and turn up the heat browning the meat well.
\n\n Step 6: \nOnce the meat is browned on all sides, add the Kashmiri chilli spices we mixed with water and fry it for 2-3 mins.
\n\n Step 7: \nStir in the whisked yogurt, a pinch of saffron (optional)and salt to taste. Cover and let the curry simmer on medium for 15 mins until the oil starts separating from the curry.
\n\n Step 8: \nOnce you see the oil start separating, add half of the powdered garam masala (whole spices) and add a cup of water to loosen the curry.
\n\n Step 9: \n You can now transfer the curry to a pressure cooker(aka Instant pot) and cook on high for 8-10 mins then natural release the pressure. Or you can lower the heat, cover the pot and allow the curry to simmer for 45mins-60 mins until the meat gets tender.
\n\n Step 10: \nCheck to see if the meat is tender (if you are cooking bone-in the meat should be falling off the bone) &amp; season with salt if needed. When it is melt-in-the mouth tender stir in the remaining garam masala powder and turn off the heat.
\n\n Step 11: \nGarnish with a handful of chopped cilantro and serve with fragrant basmati rice or Naan.\n
    </string>
    <string name="Main4">Greek Style Lamb Meatballs</string>
    <string name="Mainingredients4">
\n1 lb ground lamb
\n1/2 Cup Onion, finely diced
\n1 1/2 Tbsp Garlic, minced
\n2 Tbsp Flat Parsley, finely chopped\n
1 tsp Fennel Seeds, crushed\n
1 tsp Corriander Powder\n
1 tsp Cumin Powder\n
1/2 tsp Crushed Red Pepper\n
3 Tbsp Rice Flour\n
1 Large Egg, whisked\n
Salt &amp; Pepper to taste\n
1 Cup Plain Greek Yogurt\n
1- 2 cloves garlic\n
Salt, to taste\n
3-4 Radishes, sliced\n
1 Small Cucumber, sliced\n
    </string>
    <string name="Mainserving4">4 serving(s) </string>
    <string name="Maintime4">Prep Time: 15 minutes , Total Time: 35 minutes </string>
    <string name="Maindirections4">
Step 1: \nCombine the ground lamb, onion, galric, parsley, fennel seed, corriander powder, cumin powder, crushed red pepper, rice flour, egg, salt and pepper together well.
\n\n Step 2: \nMix with your hands if needed.
\n\n Step 3: \n Form about 20 palm sized meatballs rolling them in your hands.
\n\n Step 4: \nPlace on a parchment lined baking tray and allow to set for about 10 mins in the fridge while you preheat the oven to 450F
\n\n Step 5: \nBake the meatballs at 450F for about 15-20 minutes
\n\n Step 6: \nWhile the meatballs are cooking, mince/grate 1-2 cloves of garlic into the greek yogurt.
\n\n Step 7: \nSeason with salt and stir well.
\n\n Step 8: \nSlice the radishes &amp; cucumbers into half moons and season them with salt.
\n\n Step 9: \nTo plate spoon some of the garlic yogurt on the bottom of the pate, top with meatballs…garnish with sliced radishes &amp; cucumbers and top with mint chimichurri sauce.
\n
    </string>
    <string name="Main5">Salmon Chowder with Leeks and Potatoes </string>
    <string name="Mainingredients5">
\n3 Tbsp Butter
\n1 Leek, sliced
\n2 stalks Celery, sliced\n
4 cloves of Garlic, minced\n
2 medium Russet Potatoes, diced\n
1/2 tsp Fennel Seeds, lightly crushed\n
1 Bay Leaf\n
1 tsp dried Parsley\n
1 tsp dried Dill\n
2 Tbsp Capers with Brine\n
1 Tbsp Tomato Paste\n
4 cups Seafood/Chicken Stock\n
1/2 cup Cream Cheese\n
1 cup heavy Cream\n
1 lb Salmon, cut in chunks\n
Salt &amp; Pepper, to taste\n
    </string>
    <string name="Mainserving5">4 serving(s) </string>
    <string name="Maintime5">Prep Time: 10 minutes , Total Time: 30 minutes </string>
    <string name="Maindirections5">
Step 1 :\n
         Melt butter in a big pot on medium high.
\n\n Step 2: \n
        Add the sliced leeks and saute for 3-4 minutes until they soften.
\n\n Step 3: \n
        Add minced garlic and saute for another minute.
\n\n Step 4: \n
        Add the sliced celery, lightly crushed fennel seeds, dried parsley, dried dill, the bay leaf, salt &amp; pepper to taste, tomato paste the capers with brine &amp; diced potatoes and stir it all well.
\n\n Step 5: \n
        Add the seafood stock or chicken stock and mix everything together.
\n\n Step 6: \n
        Bring the soup to a boil, then cover and lower heat to a simmer for about 15-20 minutes until the potatoes are tender.
\n\n Step 7: \n
        Once tender, use a potato masher to mash up some of the potatoes gently. You do not want them all mashed…just a few to thicken the soup.
\n\n Step 8: \n
         Add 1/2 a cup pf cream cheese and stir it well into the soup.
\n\n Step 9: \n
        Add the chunks of salmon, cover and allow them to cook for 3-5 minutes
\n\n Step 10: \n
        Add a cup of heavy cream and stir it in gently.
\n\n Step 11: \n
        Season with salt and pepper as needed.
\n\n Step 12: \n
         Lastly garnish with fresh chopped parsley and switch off the heat.
        \n\n
    </string>
    <string name="Main6">Greek Marinated Salmon</string>
    <string name="Mainingredients6">
1 1/2 lb fresh salmon\n
2 tbsp Olive Oil (extra virgin)\n
1 tsp lemon zest\n
2 tbsp lemon juice (about 1 large lemon)\n
2 cloves of garlic\n
1 tsp salt\n
1/2 tsp fresh dill (I used freeze dried)\n
1/2 tsp dried oregano\n
1/2 tsp crushed red pepper\n
1/2 tsp sumac\n
    </string>
    <string name="Mainserving6">4 serving(s) </string>
    <string name="Maintime6">Prep Time: 30 minutes , Total Time: 50 minutes </string>
    <string name="Maindirections6">
Step 1 :\n
        Mix together the olive oil, lemon zest (about a teaspoon), the juice of the lemon (about 2 tablespoons or so), 2 cloves of garlic (grated into the bowl), the salt, fresh dill (I didn;t have any so I used freeze dried instead), dried oregano, crushed red pepper and sumac.
      \n\n Step 2: \n
        Place the salmon fillet (mine had the skin on) in a zip lock baggy and pour the mixed marinade over the salmon. Lock the bag and gently massage the marinade into the fish to coat it evenly, then refrigerate and allow the fish to marinade for about 20-30 minutes.
      \n\n Step 3: \n
        Once marinated, place the fish on a foil lined baking sheet skin-side down and bake in a 400F oven for about 15-20 minutes. Don’t forget to pour over all the marinade onto the fish. I portioned my salmon before baking, to make it easier to serve. (And don’t worry about the skin…it comes off super easily once the fish is baked). You can also grill the fish or pan fry it…whatever cooking method you want, really.
      \n\n Step 4: \n
        Serve hot with some greek salad and some cool Tzatziki Sauce over the top…yummm!
        \n
        Notes:
Sumac is a middle eastern spice that is tangy and a little tart. Do not worry if you do not have it…just add a touch more lemon zest instead.
        \n\n
    </string>
    <string name="Main7">Easy Mexican Rice</string>
    <string name="Mainingredients7">
2 tbsp Olive Oil\n
1 clove of garlic, minced
1/2 green bell pepper or 1 jalapeno, seeded and finely diced\n
2 green onions or a handful of cilantro, roughly chopped\n
1 1/2 cups of long grain rice (I use Basmati Rice)\n
1/2 cup Tomato sauce (or canned diced tomatoes if you want chunky tomato pieces in the rice)\n
3 Cups of chicken broth/stock\n
1 tsp salt (or according to taste if the chicken broth is salty)\n
1/3 tsp ground black pepper\n
1/2 tsp dried oregano\n
    </string>
    <string name="Mainserving7">3 serving(s) </string>
    <string name="Maintime7">Prep Time: 15 minutes , Total Time: 40 minutes </string>
    <string name="Maindirections7">
Step 1 :\n
        Heat 2 tbsp of olive oil in a deep pan, on medium-high heat.
        \n\n Step 2: \n
        Add the minced garlic and sautee for a minute or two, until it’s soft.
        \n\n Step 3: \n
        Toss in the diced green pepper/ jalapeno and sautee it together with the garlic.
        \n\n Step 4: \n
        Before your garlic starts burning, add the rice and stir it well so that more or less each grain is coated in oil. Sautee the rice for a couple minutes stirring to make sure the rice doesn’t stick to the bottom of the pan.
        \n\n Step 5: \n
        Then add 1/2 cup of tomato sauce or diced tomatoes (according to your preference) and stir it all to coat the rice.
        \n\n Step 6: \n
        Pour in the chicken stock/broth and stir picking up all the flavor from the bottom of the pan.
        \n\n Step 7: \n
        Season the rice with salt, pepper and oregano. Stir gently and let the broth come to a boil on high heat.
        \n\n Step 8: \n
        As soon as the liquid starts bubbling, put a lid on and turn the heat down to a low simmer and let the rice cook for about 20 mins, until most of the liquid is absorbed and the rice is tender. Add the chopped green onion or cilantro and very gently stir it in, or simple fluff the rice up with some forks.
       \n\n Step 9: \n
        Garnish with a little green onion on top.
        \n\n

    </string>
    <string name="Main8">Palak Paneer</string>
    <string name="Mainingredients8">
1-1.5 cups Paneer* cubed\n
3- 4 cups Spinach packed\n
2-3 tbsp oil/butter as needed\n
2-3 green chilies (thai peppers) adjust to your spice level\n
3/4 cup onion diced or blended\n
1 tsp garlic-ginger paste\n
1/2 cup tomatoes diced or puree\n
1/2 tsp kasuri methi (dried fenugreek leaves) (optional but recomended if available)\n
8 cashews soaked in warm water &amp; blended to a paste\n
1/4 cup heavy cream\n
        inch cinnamon stick\n
2-3 green cardamom pods\n
2-3 cloves\n
1/4 tsp cumin seeds\n
        1 tsp coriander powder\n
1/2 tsp garam masala\n
    </string>
    <string name="Mainserving8">4 serving(s) </string>
    <string name="Maintime8">Prep Time: 30 minutes , Total Time: 45 minutes </string>
    <string name="Maindirections8">
Step 1 :\n
        Add a teaspoon oil in a pan and add the sliced green chilies and spinach leaves. Cook the leaves until just wilted, but avoid overcooking to retain its vibrant green color. Set aside to cool.
        \n\n Step 2: \n
        Once cooled blend the spinach and green chilies to a smooth puree.
        \n\n Step 3: \n
        To make the gravy- heat oil in a pan and add the whole spices. as soon as they begin to splutter add the onions and sauté on medium high heat until they turn translucent.
        \n\n Step 4: \n
        Add the ginger garlic paste and fry until the raw smell goes away.
        \n\n Step 5: \n
        Add the tomatoes and season with salt. cook the tomatoes down until they turn mushy.
        \n\n Step 6: \n
        The add the kasuri methi and spice powders and fry the mixture until it starts releasing oil.
        \n\n Step 7: \n
        Pour in half a cup of water and stir until the mixture thickens.
        \n\n Step 8: \n
        Lower the heat and add the spinach puree. mix well until it comes to a gentle simmer.
        \n\n Step 9: \n
        (optional) Pan fry the paneer cubes with 1-2 tsp oil for 2-3 mins until golden on each side in a separate pan. Add the paneer cubes to the spinach mixture and turn off the heat.
        \n\n Step 10: \n
        Add the cashew paste mixed with the cream and stir it in for added creaminess. Reserve some for garnish.
        \n\n

    </string>
    <string name="Main9"> Turkish Salad</string>
    <string name="Mainingredients9">
1 head of romaine lettuce\n
1/2 large cucumber (or 1 small)\n
2 large tomatoes\n
1/4 green bell pepper\n
1/4 red bell pepper\n
1/2 a small red onion\n
1 clove of garlic\n
Juice of one lemon (2-3 tbsp)\n
1 tsp salt\n
1/2 tsp fresh ground black pepper\n
2 tbsp extra virgin olive oil\n
6-8 fresh mint leaves, finely sliced\n
1/3 cup fresh flat-leaf parsley, finely chopped\n
1/2 tsp sumac\n
feta cheese and black onlives for garnish\n
    </string>
    <string name="Mainserving9">2 serving(s) </string>
    <string name="Maintime9">Prep Time: 10 minutes , Total Time: 30 minutes </string>
    <string name="Maindirections9">
Step 1 :\n
        Chop the lettuce in bite-size pieces. De-seed (optional) and chop the cucumber and tomatoes. Seed the the peppers, remove the cores and cut the flesh into thin strips. Cut the red onion in half, peel and finely slice it. Then toss all the chopped veggies into a large bowl.
        \n\n Step 2: \n
        To make the dressing crush, peel and finely mince the clove of garlic. Add to it the juice of a large lemon, salt, pepper, olive oil, the finely chopped mint and parsley and sumac. Whisk everything together.
        \n\n Step 3: \n
        Pour the dressing over the salad and toss lightly. Serve garnished with feta cheese cubes and some black olives.
        \n\n
    </string>
    <string name="Main10">Lasagna Rolls</string>
    <string name="Mainingredients10">
12 uncooked lasagna sheets\n
2 Tbsp extra virgin olive oil\n
1/2 lb ground turkey/ ground beef\n
1/2 an onion\n
3-4 cloves of garlic\n
2 cups of crushed tomatoes or tomato puree\n
2 Tbsp dried Italian seasoning (mix herbs)\n
1 tsp dried red pepper flakes (optional for heat)\n
Salt and ground black pepper, to taste\n
1 (15 oz) container Ricotta Cheese\n
1 large egg\n
2 handfuls of fresh flat leaf parsley\n
1 cup grated Mozzarella Cheese, divided\n
1 cup freshly grated Parmesan Cheese\n
1 tsp salt\n
1/2 tsp freshly ground black pepper\n
    </string>
    <string name="Mainserving10">12 serving(s) </string>
    <string name="Maintime10">Prep Time: 20 minutes , Total Time: 1 hour 10 minutes</string>
    <string name="Maindirections10">
Step 1 :\n
        Finely chop the onion and garlic
\n\n Step 2: \n
        Heat the olive oil in a deep fry pan and saute the garlic and onion till soft. Add the ground turkey/ beef and stir to break up the meat.
\n\n Step 3: \nSeason the meat with Salt, pepper, the Italian seasoning (mix herbs) and red pepper flakes for heat and let the meat cook and brown.
\n\n Step 4: \n For restaurant style meat sauce, drain the meat of any excess fat in the pan and pulse the meat mix in a food processor for about minute until the meat breaks down into smaller grains.(you can skip this step if it’s too much hassle and you like the rustic-ness of homemade meat sauce).
\n\n Step 5: \n Return the meat to the pan and add the tomato puree or crushed tomatoes. If you use tomato puree you may have to add about a cup of water. Let it simmer gently for about 10-15 minutes. Taste and check for seasoning.
\n\n Step 6: \n While that’s bubbling away you can get started with lasagna sheets. Cook the lasagna sheets in salted water according to the instructions on the packet.
\n\n Step 7: \n In a mixing bowl, add the ricotta cheese, half the mozzarella, half the parmesan cheese, a handful of parsley, an egg, salt and pepper and mix well.
\n\n Step 8: \n To assemble the lasagna rolls, lay the sheets out on parchment or wax paper. Spread the ricotta cheese mix along the sheets, then spoon some of the meat mix on each sheet as well. Roll up each of the lasagna sheets individually.
\n\n Step 9: \n In the bottom of the baking dish you’re going to use, spread a thin layer of the meat sauce. Then place the lasagna rolls in the dish and top with some more meat sauce. Spread the remaining mozzarella, parmesan cheese and parsley evenly over the top.
\n\n Step 10: \n Cover the dish with foil making sure it’s not touching the cheese at all and bake at 375F for  35-40 minutes.
\n\n
    </string>
</resources>